export default  [
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "When was the GPT3 model released?",
    "correct_answer": "2020",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "2016",
        "2021",
        "2023"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "How large is the dataset of GPT3?",
    "correct_answer": "GPT-3 is trained on 750 gigabites of data",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "GPT-3 is trained on 200 gigabites of data",
        "GPT-3 is trained on 500 gigabites of data",
        "GPT-3 is tained on 1 petabyte of data"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "On how many GPUs was the GPT3 model trained?",
    "correct_answer": "This information is not disclosed",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "50000 GPUs",
        "8192 GPUs",
        "3000 GPUs"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is transfer learning?",
    "correct_answer": "All of them",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "transfer learning can be used to fine-tune pre-trained models such as GPT-3 for specific tasks",
        "a machine learning technique",
        "training of one task is re-purposed on a second related task"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "MLOps stands for ...",
    "correct_answer": "Machine Learning Operations",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Master Language Operators",
        "Microsoft Linguistic Ops",
        "Managed Loop Ops"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is a diffusion model?",
    "correct_answer": "All of them",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "a class of generative models that can be used for image synthesis",
        "are based on the idea of iteratively refining a noise source until it becomes an image",
        "have been shown to outperform GANs on image synthesis tasks"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Recently the SAM project was released by Meta, what does it stands for?",
    "correct_answer": "Segment Anything Model",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Segment AI Model",
        "Special AI Model",
        "Segment Ant Model"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is Microsoft role in the whole OpenAI story?",
    "correct_answer": "Microsoft and OpenAI have a unique partnership",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "OpenAI is sold to Microsoft",
        "Microsoft created OpenAI",
        "Microsoft and OpenAI are not related, they just use similar names"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is Azure Cognitive Search?",
    "correct_answer": "It provides a dedicated search engine and persistent storage of your searchable content for full text search scenarios. ",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "It is a cognitive service in azure",
        "It is a service like bing that allows you to search the internet",
        "It is a service that allows you to search the datasources that you need, without configuration"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is MLFlow? ",
    "correct_answer": "MLflow is an open-source platform for managing the end-to-end machine learning lifecycle",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "MLflow is a model that’s only used for managing models",
        "MLflow is a model that’s only used for cloud portability",
        "MLflow is a model that’s only used for tracking experiments"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Can you run Databricks on Azure?",
    "correct_answer": "Yes, it's even a first class citizen",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "No",
        "Yes, but only in an unsupported way",
        "Yes, but only in a hybrid way. Most of it needs to run on premise"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Does Azure has a service for running Apache Spark?",
    "correct_answer": "Yes, via Azure Synapse and DataBricks.",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "No",
        "Only via a custom solution",
        "You need to set up several VMs, and manage this yourself."
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is the difference between Databricks and Azure Synpase?",
    "correct_answer": "All of them",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "They have different capabilities and integrations",
        "Synapse integrates seamlessly with other Azure services, while Databricks requires API integrations",
        "Both offer great data protection, access control, network security and threat protection"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is Microsoft Copilot?",
    "correct_answer": " Copilot combines the power of large language models (LLMs) with your data in the Microsoft Graphand the Microsoft 365 apps to turn your words into the most powerful productivity tool on the planet",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Copilot is a model that’s only used for tracking experiments",
        "Copilot is a tool that can help you in Microsoft Flight simulator",
        "Microsoft Copilot helps you write code"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is an LLM?",
    "correct_answer": "Large Language Model",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Linked Linguistic Matching",
        "Logical Link Model",
        "Logical Linguistic Matching"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "You would like to summarize a paragraph of text. Which generative AI model family would you use to solve for this workload?",
    "correct_answer": "GPT-3",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Dall-E",
        "Codex",
        "Florence"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What are some of the use cases of Azure OpenAI Service?",
    "correct_answer": "All of them",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Content generation",
        "Summarization",
        "Code Generation"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is a limitation of using Azure OpenAI Service APIs?",
    "correct_answer": "Number of tokens per minute per model",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Number of languages supported",
        "Number of features",
        "All of them"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is Codex?",
    "correct_answer": "None of them",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "It is a model that is only proficient in C#",
        "It is a model that is only proficient in Perl",
        "It is a model that is only proficient in PHP"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Few-shot prompting",
    "correct_answer": "is a technique that allows a model to learn from a small number of examples.",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "is a technique that allows a model to learn from only one example.",
        "is a technique that allows a model to learn from only text data.",
        "is a technique that allows a model to learn from only image data."
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Chain of thought prompting",
    "correct_answer": "Chain-of-Thought Prompting is a technique that generates a series of intermediate reasoning steps",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Chain-of-Thought Prompting is a technique that is used to limit the possible options of the model",
        "to limit the possible options of a model",
        "It's a technique that generates a series of intermediate reasoning steps that significantly improves the ability of small language models to perform complex reasoning."
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is semantic kernel?",
    "correct_answer": "an SDK that enables advanced development with OpenAI ",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Semantic Kernel does not enable integration of AI Large Language Models (LLMs) with conventional programming languages",
        "It's a unix kernel",
        "only works with Python"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What are embeddings?",
    "correct_answer": "Embeddings make it easier to do machine learning on large inputs representing words by capturing the semantic similarities in a vector space",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Embeddings are only used for natural language processing tasks",
        "The distance between two embeddings in the vector space is not correlated with semantic similarity between two inputs in the original format",
        "Embeddings are only used for supervised learning tasks"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "How much is Microsoft going to invest in OpenAI?",
    "correct_answer": "10B$",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "200B$",
        "5B$",
        "1B$"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "How can you interact with the Azure OpenAI service?",
    "correct_answer": "All of them",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "API",
        "Web Based InterFace (Azure OpenAI Studio)",
        "Python SDK"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which Model does not (yet) exist?",
    "correct_answer": "GPT-5",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "GPT-4",
        "Codex",
        "DALL-E"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "When will ChatGPT (chat-35-turbo) become available in Europe?",
    "correct_answer": "Last week",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Next week",
        "Someday",
        "Unknown"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What would be valid reasons to choose Azure OpenAI over OpenAI?",
    "correct_answer": "All of them",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure OpenAI will not learn from your data",
        "Azure OpenAI models can be deployed in Europe",
        "Your data is your data"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "OpenAI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "How can you make the 'chat' behave in a certain way?",
    "correct_answer": "With the system message",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "By deploying a specific model",
        "This is not possible",
        "By asking it nicely"
      ]
  }
]